I have 10 years of experience - 5 years in corporate and 5 years in startups. I know breadth, a bit more than depth. I work on Nodejs/Javaplay server dev, Android/iOS native, Angular/Backbone, some data science algorithms and embedded stacks/C/C++.

## **Employment Experience Overview**

Period	Org.	Responsibilities	Highlights
Since Nov 2015	Consultant JioMoney	Server development for mass transit application (Since May).	We are building a redbus like service using NodeJS in the backend.
	Reliance	Server development for mobile wallet (Feb - May)	Started the work of writing JioWallet server using JavaPlay framework. I worked building the first version of the server - though it was not a scalable version - but was more of an exercise towards the same.
		Automated testcases for android and iOS apps (Dec -Jan)	I developed calabash based automated testcases for Android and iOS, a part of JioMoney release process. I got very interesting insights into challenges faced by testers and how automation can be employed to solve CI/CD challenges faced by orgs.
July 2010 - Feb 2009	Qualcomm	Customer issues related to audio multimedia and stability	I was a single Hyderbad PoC for any multimedia audio issues on Qualcomm chipsets Arm 9 + Arm 11 and Arm 9 + Scorpian chipsets, coordinating across multiple teams and spread across regions.
Jan 2009 - July 2006	Conexant /NXP Semi- conductors	Open source tools and technologies (mainly linux kernel) and BSP development for set-top-boxes.	Suggested a patch to Linux kernel community, titled "O_DIRECT patch for processors with VIPT cache for mainline kernel" (Link: <a href="goo.gl/2QEwGi">goo.gl/2QEwGi</a> )

#### Open source and patents

Period	Project Title	Highlights
2015	Archiejs – a nodejs DI framework	An open-source nodejs dependency injection framework suitable for managing large nodejs applications.
Open		(https://github.com/archiejs)
source and products	Experiments in content, news and e-learning	Applied for a US patent on search technology (goo.gl/KTiFn1)

## **Startup Experience Overview**

Period	Internal Projects	Highlights
2015	A education app	Building video application on iOS for creating video abstracts,
Proof of	Demo on request  A fashion tech product	video blogs and other knowledge transfer usecases.
concepts	A rasmon tech product	I worked for a few months on a fashion technology product where users can try garments online. I made a POC and here is a video link to it - click to see the demo
2012 -2015	Self owned IT services company with a team of 5 members in past	I was involved in getting business and delivering software products. We have build various apps for our clients. Building Mobile and Webs Products on Android, iOS and MEAN stack.
Mostly services		(Website: <a href="http://flipflopapp.com/">http://flipflopapp.com/</a> , Github: <a href="goo.gl/mHFFlw">goo.gl/mHFFlw</a> )
Mid 2011 - July 2010	EDEDAA – Art exhibitions along staircases in corporates	I was the Curator & Planner of a startup in arts industry (http://ededaa.blogsopt.in)

# **Technical competency**

Year	Role	Modules, Projects and Technologies
2011 -16	Consulting for web and mobile applications	<u>Live services &amp; products</u> : Built various mobile applications and websites. <u>Languages</u> : nodejs, java play framework, android (java), swift (ios), angular (backbone, sencha touch), C/openCV etc
2009	Android audio multimedia Customer Engineer	Products: LG GT540 (Optimus), Samsung Galaxymany more of 7x series Modules: Android music application, Android framework classes, Opencore PVMF, Userspace HAL, Audio drivers, Hardware drivers for audio devices (like headset, BT headset, etc), proprietary audio routing mechanisms, etc Languages: C, C++, Java Other responsibilities: Customer training, Documentation, Software architecture support for customers
2006 -09	Engineer in Open source and BSP team working on Set-top- boxes	Products: Nevis, Pecos, Trinity (and variants)  Modules: Linux kernel, Uboot, Proprietary kernel abstraction layer (in kernel space and user space), Busybox, Uclibc library, GDB, etc  BSP areas: Arm 11 application processor bring-up, porting Uboot, Memory management related issues, Arm related issues (caching), etc  Languages: C, Arm assembly, Lauterbach scripting, Makefiles

## **Educational Data**

Degree	Year	University	Highlights
Master of Computer Applications	2006	Guru Gobind Singh Indrap. Univ. (GGSIPU)	Algebraic study of discrete multidimensional signal processing, unpublished work, MCA 3 <sup>rd</sup> sem, 2004 (goo.gl/97LYOd)
Bachelor of Computer Applications	2003	Delhi University	Tried to build a very primitive OS in assembly language

# **Personal Data**

Date of Birth, Nationality	27-11-81, INDIAN
Languages	English, Hindi
Github	http://www.github.com/archiejs, http://www.github.com/flipflopapp
Engineering Blog	https://medium.com/engineering-notes